Outer Banks History Center Ephemera Collection PC.5276
State Archives of North Carolina
- North Carolina Counties, 1798-2019 and undated; 43990; Outer Banks History Center
  - Dare, 1881-2019 and undated; 4659; Outer Banks History Center
    - Businesses, 1901-2018 and undated; 4664; Outer Banks History Center
      The Businesses subseries contains materials created by or related to various business operating in Dare County. The materials in this subseries primarily consist of brochures and pamphlets, restaurant menus, flyers, coupons, advertisements, and other printed material. Businesses represented include retail stores, restaurants, hotels and motels, healthcare service providers, transportation, and public media, as well as some businesses that operate under the aegis of the State of North Carolina (such as Roanoke Island Festival Park and the North Carolina Aquarium). Folders labeled "accommodations" may include documentation of vacation rental cottages, campgrounds, and other types of accommodations, in addition to hotels, motels, and inns.
      - Business Directories, 1963-2017; 4745; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Business Directories)
      - Carolinian Hotel (Nags Head), 1949-1985 and undated; 4746; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Carolinian Hotel (Nags Head))
      - Colington Island Businesses, 1963-1995; 4747; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Colington Island Businesses)
      - College of the Albemarle, 1989-2014; 4748; Outer Banks History Center (Folder College of the Albemarle)
      - Dare County Accommodations, 1996-2016 and undated; 4749; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Accommodations)
      - Dare County Airport, 1950s-2012; 4750; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Airport)
      - Dare County Businesses (General), 1954-2017; 4751; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Businesses (General))
      - Duck Businesses, 1977-2016 and undated; 4752; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Duck Businesses)
      - Galleon Esplanade (Nags Head), 1973-1985 and undated; 5058; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Galleon Esplanade (Nags Head))
      - Hatteras Island Accommodations, circa 1940s-1996 and undated; 5059; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Hatteras Island Accommodations)
      - Hatteras Island Businesses, 1966-1995 and undated; 4755; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Hatteras Island Businesses)
      - Hatteras Island Restaurants, circa 1960s-1990s; 4756; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Hatteras Island Restaurants)
      - Healthcare, 1976-2008 and undated; 4757; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Healthcare)
      - Island Gallery and Christmas Shop (Manteo), 1967-1980s; 5063; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Island Gallery and Christmas Shop (Manteo))
      - Kill Devil Hills Accommodations, 1950s-2010s; 5064; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Kill Devil Hills Accommodations)
      - Kill Devil Hills Businesses, 1966-2011; 4760; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Kill Devil Hills Businesses)
      - Kill Devil Hills Restaurants, 1979-1995 and undated; 4761; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Kill Devil Hills Restaurants)
      - Kitty Hawk Accommodations, circa 1950s-1993; 4762; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Kitty Hawk Accommodations)
      - Kitty Hawk Businesses, 1979-2000 and undated; 5068; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Kitty Hawk Businesses)
      - Kitty Hawk Kites, 1978-2010s and undated; 5069; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Kitty Hawk Kites)
      - Kitty Hawk Restaurants, circa 1980s-1990s; 4765; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Kitty Hawk Restaurants)
      - Manteo Accommodations, circa 1950s-1994 and undated; 4766; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Manteo Accommodations)
      - Manteo Businesses, 1901-1999 and undated; 4767; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Manteo Businesses)
      - Manteo Restaurants, 1995-2010s and undated; 5073; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Manteo Restaurants)
      - Manteo Retail Stores, circa 1980s-1999 and undated; 5074; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Manteo Retail Stores)
      - Nags Head Accommodations, circa 1950s-2002; 4770; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Nags Head Accommodations)
      - Nags Head Businesses, circa 1970s-2018 and undated; 4771; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Nags Head Businesses)
      - Nags Head Restaurants, circa 1960s-2010s; 4772; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Nags Head Restaurants)
      - North Carolina Aquarium, 1980s-2000s; 5078; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Aquarium)
      - North Carolina Books (Kitty Hawk), 1959-1975; 5079; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Carolina Books (Kitty Hawk))
      - Outer Banks Hospital, 2008-2014; 4775; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Outer Banks Hospital)
      - Outer Banks Promotional Brochures, circa 1940s-2000s; 4776; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Outer Banks Promotional Brochures)
      - Outer Banks Visitors Guide, 2015-2018; 4777; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Outer Banks Visitors Guide)
      - R&R Junction (Nags Head), 1975-1978 and undated; 5083; Outer Banks History Center (Folder R&R Junction (Nags Head))
      - Restaurant Guides, 1987-2017 and undated; 5084; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Restaurant Guides)
      - Roanoke Island Businesses, 1907-2015; 4780; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Roanoke Island Businesses)
      - Roanoke Island Festival Park [3 folders], 1991-2016; 4781; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Roanoke Island Festival Park [3 folders])
      - Seafare Restaurant (Nags Head), 1974-1976 and undated; 4782; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Seafare Restaurant (Nags Head))
      - Sea Ranch Hotel (Kill Devil Hills), 1956-1986; 4783; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Sea Ranch Hotel (Kill Devil Hills))
      - Southern Shores Businesses, circa 1950s-1999 and undated; 5089; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Southern Shores Businesses)
      - Transportation, 1959-1999 and undated; 4785; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Transportation)
      - Walter Greshams Outer Banks Calendar, 1983-1986; 4786; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Walter Greshams Outer Banks Calendar)
      - Walter Greshams Outer Banks Calendar [2 folders], 1987-2000; 4787; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Walter Greshams Outer Banks Calendar [2 folders])
      - Wanchese Seafood Industrial Park, 1981; 5093; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Wanchese Seafood Industrial Park)
      - Wedding Guides, 1998-2016; 4789; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Wedding Guides)
      - WVOD (Manteo), 1992-1998; 4790; Outer Banks History Center (Folder WVOD (Manteo))
    - Events, 1858-2019 and undated; 4665; Outer Banks History Center
      This subseries contains flyers, brochures, pamphlets, programs, posters, and (occasionally) planning materials and reports related to events held in and around Dare County, or organized by Dare County groups. Events include concerts, anniversaries, celebrations, dramatic performances (including documentation of works by local playwright lebame houston), exhibitions, and festivals. The Festivals folder includes a flyer for the first annual OBX Pridefest, held in 2011. Of note in this subseries are planning materials and publicity for events surrounding America's 400th Anniversary, 1984-1987; commemorative materials from various anniversaries of the Wright Brothers' first flight in 1903; and programs from early instances of the Pirates Jamboree, a multi-day celebration designed to bring vacationers to the Outer Banks in the spring season. In addition to the events documented in this subseries, event flyers and other documentation of events in Dare County may also appear in other subseries, filed under the organizing entity's name.
      - Americas 400th Anniversary, 1982-1987; 4791; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Americas 400th Anniversary)
        - Educational Pamphlets, 1987; 23011; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Educational Pamphlets)
        - Event Programs, 1984-1987; 23012; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Event Programs)
        - Planning Materials and Reports, 1982-1987; 23013; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Planning Materials and Reports)
      - Art Classes, 1956-1985; 4792; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Art Classes)
      - Aycock Brown Essay Contest, circa 1989; 4793; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Aycock Brown Essay Contest)
      - Babe Ruth World Series, 1994-1998; 4794; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Babe Ruth World Series)
      - Bloody Mary & the Virgin Queen, 2001-2006; 4796; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Bloody Mary & the Virgin Queen)
      - Bonner Bridge Shipwreck T-Shirt, 1990; 4795; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Bonner Bridge Shipwreck T-Shirt)
      - Concerts, 1958-2016; 4797; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Concerts)
      - Dare County Centennial, 1970; 4798; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Centennial)
      - Dare Day, 1975-2000; 4799; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare Day)
      - Elizabethan Rendezvous, 2002-2004; 4800; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Elizabethan Rendezvous)
      - Elizabeth R [3 folders], 1994-1995; 4801; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Elizabeth R [3 folders])
      - Event Posters [3 folders], circa 1858-2019; 4802; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Event Posters [3 folders])
      - Exhibitions, 1976-2006 and undated; 4803; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Exhibitions)
      - Festivals, 2011-2012; 4804; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Festivals)
      - First Flight Commemorations, 1948-1952; 4805; Outer Banks History Center (Folder First Flight Commemorations)
      - First Flight Commemorations, 1953; 4806; Outer Banks History Center (Folder First Flight Commemorations)
      - First Flight Commemorations, 1957-1978; 4807; Outer Banks History Center (Folder First Flight Commemorations)
      - First Flight Commemorations, 2003; 4808; Outer Banks History Center (Folder First Flight Commemorations)
      - First Flight Commemorations, 2005-2015; 4809; Outer Banks History Center (Folder First Flight Commemorations)
      - Hatteras Island Civil War Conference, 1999; 4810; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Hatteras Island Civil War Conference)
      - Hayman Clan Reunion, 1980-1995; 4811; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Hayman Clan Reunion)
      - Hurricanes, 1964-1998 and undated; 4812; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Hurricanes)
      - Land of Beginnings Festival, 2006-2011; 4813; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Land of Beginnings Festival)
      - Lectures and Presentations, 1947-2015; 4814; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Lectures and Presentations)
      - Legislative Weekend, May-98; 4815; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Legislative Weekend)
      - Miss Dare County Pageant, 1968-1987; 4816; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Miss Dare County Pageant)
      - North Beach Sun Trashfest/Big Sweep, 1991-1995; 4817; Outer Banks History Center (Folder North Beach Sun Trashfest/Big Sweep)
      - Outer Banks History Center 20th Anniversary, 2009; 4818; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Outer Banks History Center 20th Anniversary)
      - Outer Banks Seafood Festival, 2013; 4819; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Outer Banks Seafood Festival)
      - Pirates Jamboree, 1956-1958; 4820; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Pirates Jamboree)
      - Pirates Jamboree [2 folders], 1959-1964; 4821; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Pirates Jamboree [2 folders])
      - Plays and Dramatic Performances, 1975-2010s and undated; 4822; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Plays and Dramatic Performances)
      - Roanoke Decoded Symposium, 1993; 4823; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Roanoke Decoded Symposium)
      - Virginia Dare Day, 1962; 4824; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Virginia Dare Day)
      - Visit of Governors to Dare County, 1957; 4825; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Visit of Governors to Dare County)
      - Wanchese Seafood Festival, 1994-1996; 4826; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Wanchese Seafood Festival)
    - Recreation, 1881-2014 and undated; 4666; Outer Banks History Center
      The Recreation subseries, 1881-2014 and undated, contains pamphlets and programs related to recreational activities in and around Dare County, such as boating, fishing, and sports. Of note in this subseries are brochures for Camp Seatone, a children's summer camp in Manteo; an 1881 prospectus for the Kitty Hawk Bay Sportsman's Club; and programs from numerous sportfishing tournaments, including the International Blue Marlin Tournament, the Nags Head Surf Fishing Tournament, and fishing tournaments organized by the Pirate's Cove community.
      - Air Tours, undated; 4827; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Air Tours)
      - Bicycling, 1996 and undated; 4828; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Bicycling)
      - Boating, 1961-1990s; 4829; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Boating)
      - Camp Seatone (Manteo), 1939 and undated; 4830; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Camp Seatone (Manteo))
      - Fishing [2 folders], 1952-2014; 4831; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Fishing [2 folders])
      - General, 1984-1995 and undated; 4832; Outer Banks History Center (Folder General)
      - Golf and Tennis, 1976-1996 and undated; 4833; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Golf and Tennis)
      - Hatteras Island Recreation, 1980-2005 and undated; 4834; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Hatteras Island Recreation)
      - Hunting, 1993-1994 and undated; 4835; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Hunting)
      - International Blue Marlin Tournament, 1959-1975; 4836; Outer Banks History Center (Folder International Blue Marlin Tournament)
      - Kill Devil Hills Recreation, circa 1960s-2005; 4837; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Kill Devil Hills Recreation)
      - Kitty Hawk Bay Sportsmans Club, 1881; 4838; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Kitty Hawk Bay Sportsmans Club)
      - Manteo Recreation, 1992-2006 and undated; 4839; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Manteo Recreation)
      - Nags Head Surf Fishing Tournament [4 folders], 1952-1973; 4840; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Nags Head Surf Fishing Tournament [4 folders])
      - Nags Head Surf Fishing Tournament [5 folders], 1974-1985; 4841; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Nags Head Surf Fishing Tournament [5 folders])
      - Nags Head Surf Fishing Tournament [2 folders], 1987-1990; 4842; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Nags Head Surf Fishing Tournament [2 folders])
      - Nags Head Surf Fishing Tournament, 1999; 4843; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Nags Head Surf Fishing Tournament)
      - Nags Head Recreation, 1961-2011; 4844; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Nags Head Recreation)
      - Pirates Cove Fishing Tournaments, 1992-2007; 4845; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Pirates Cove Fishing Tournaments)
      - Roanoke Island Recreation, 1975 - 2005; 4846; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Roanoke Island Recreation)
      - Running and Races, 2009-2014; 4847; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Running and Races)
      - Southern Shores Recreation, circa 1960s-2005; 4848; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Southern Shores Recreation)
    - Government and Public Services, 1898-2017 and undated; 4667; Outer Banks History Center
      This subseries contains circulars, pamphlets, brochures, event flyers, reports, and other printed material related to Dare County offices, government, and public services. Included in this subseries are materials related to parks, monuments, memorials, and other public spaces in Dare County, as well as promotional materials produced by Dare County's municipal offices.
      - Cape Hatteras National Seashore [2 folders], 1952-2010 and undated; 4849; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Cape Hatteras National Seashore [2 folders])
      - Dare County Agricultural Extension Service, 1989-1998 and undated; 4850; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Agricultural Extension Service)
      - Dare County Board of Education, 1965-2005; 4851; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Board of Education)
      - Dare County Commissioners, 1963-2014; 4852; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Commissioners)
      - Dare County Department of Adult Services, 1988-2017; 4853; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Department of Adult Services)
      - Dare County Government, 1921-2011; 4854; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Government)
      - Dare County Government, 1921-2011; 4855; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Government)
      - Dare County Health Department, 1962-1999; 4856; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Health Department)
      - Dare County Parks and Recreation Department, 1995-2003 and undated; 4857; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Parks and Recreation Department)
      - Dare County Public Information Office, 1999-2000; 4858; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Public Information Office)
      - Dare County Public Library, 1985-2013 and undated; 4859; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Public Library)
      - Dare County Public Works, 1990-1993 and undated; 4860; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Public Works)
      - Dare County Schools [2 folders], 1898-2016; 4861; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Schools [2 folders])
      - Dare County Sheriffs Department, 1974-1996 and undated; 4862; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Dare County Sheriffs Department)
      - Elizabeth II State Historic Site, 1982-2009; 4863; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Elizabeth II State Historic Site)
      - Elizabethan Gardens [2 folders], 1965-2010 and undated; 4864; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Elizabethan Gardens [2 folders])
      - Ft. Raleigh National Historic Site, 1942-2012 and undated; 4865; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Ft. Raleigh National Historic Site)
      - Graveyard of the Atlantic Museum, 1987-2015; 4866; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Graveyard of the Atlantic Museum)
      - Jockeys Ridge State Park, 1988-2009 and undated; 4867; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Jockeys Ridge State Park)
      - Nags Head Woods Preserve, 1991-2002; 4868; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Nags Head Woods Preserve)
      - Outer Banks History Center, 1988-2011; 4869 (Folder Outer Banks History Center)
      - Outer Banks History Center Programs, 1991-2015; 4870; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Outer Banks History Center Programs)
      - Pea Island National Wildlife Refuge, 1954-2002 and undated; 4871; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Pea Island National Wildlife Refuge)
      - Soil and Water Conservation District, 1987; 4872; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Soil and Water Conservation District)
      - Town of Kill Devil Hills, 1989-2003 and undated; 4873; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Town of Kill Devil Hills)
      - Town of Manteo, circa 1950s-2010s; 4874; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Town of Manteo)
      - Town of Nags Head, 1999-2013; 4875; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Town of Nags Head)
      - United States Coast Guard Group Cape Hatteras, 1939-2014; 4876; Outer Banks History Center (Folder United States Coast Guard Group Cape Hatteras)
      - Wright Brothers National Memorial, 1942-2016; 4877; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Wright Brothers National Memorial)
    - Real Estate, 1927-2016 and undated; 4668; Outer Banks History Center
      The Real Estate subseries, 1927-2016 and undated, contains promotional brochures and pamphlets related to real estate in Dare County. Materials in this collection document homes marketed for sale in the Outer Banks as well as vacation rental properties maintained by various rental companies. Documents may be arranged by company (such as Sun Realty or Britt Real Estate) or by neighborhood/community (such as First Flight Village, Mirlo Beach, or Pirate's Cove) as appropriate. Of note in this subseries is an early booklet (1927) advertising the Virginia Dare Shores community, one of the earliest housing subdivisions on the Outer Banks, developed by Frank Stick in present-day Kill Devil Hills.
      - Atlantic Realty, 1983-1996; 4878; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Atlantic Realty)
      - Barrier Island Station (Duck), 1983-1984; 4879; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Barrier Island Station (Duck))
      - Britt Real Estate (Duck), 1984-1995; 4880; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Britt Real Estate (Duck))
      - Colony Realty (Avon), 1981-1986 and undated; 4881; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Colony Realty (Avon))
      - Cove Realty (Nags Head), 1983-1995; 4882; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Cove Realty (Nags Head))
      - Duck Real Estate, 1983-1993; 4883; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Duck Real Estate)
      - First Flight Village (Kill Devil Hills), undated; 4884; Outer Banks History Center (Folder First Flight Village (Kill Devil Hills))
      - Hatteras Island Real Estate, 1966-1997; 4885; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Hatteras Island Real Estate)
      - Hatteras Realty, 1983-1994; 4886; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Hatteras Realty)
      - Homes & Land Magazine, 1984-2016; 4887; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Homes & Land Magazine)
      - Homes Magazine, 1978-1988; 4888; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Homes Magazine)
      - Joe Lamb, Jr., 1972-1993; 4889; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Joe Lamb, Jr.)
      - Kill Devil Hills Real Estate, circa 1950s-2014; 4890; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Kill Devil Hills Real Estate)
      - Kings Grant Realty (Nags Head), 1983-1990; 4891; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Kings Grant Realty (Nags Head))
      - Kitty Dunes Realty, 1981-1995; 4892; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Kitty Dunes Realty)
      - Kitty Hawk Real Estate, 1966-1985 and undated; 4893; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Kitty Hawk Real Estate)
      - Kitty Hawk Rentals, 1990-1995; 4894; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Kitty Hawk Rentals)
      - Mirlo Beach (Rodanthe), 1988-1989; 4895; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Mirlo Beach (Rodanthe))
      - Nags Head Real Estate, 1981-1995; 4896; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Nags Head Real Estate)
      - Nags Head Realty, 1984-1996; 4897; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Nags Head Realty)
      - Ocean Acres (Kill Devil Hills), circa 1960s; 4898; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Ocean Acres (Kill Devil Hills))
      - Old Nags Head Cove, undated; 4899; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Old Nags Head Cove)
      - Outer Banks Beach Club (Kill Devil Hills), circa 1980s; 4900; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Outer Banks Beach Club (Kill Devil Hills))
      - Outer Banks Homes Guide, 1992-1995; 4901; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Outer Banks Homes Guide)
      - Outer Banks Home Tour Guides, 1996, 2016; 4902; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Outer Banks Home Tour Guides)
      - Outer Banks Ltd., 1981-1996; 4903; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Outer Banks Ltd.)
      - Outer Beaches Realty (Avon), 1985-1996; 4904; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Outer Beaches Realty (Avon))
      - Pirates Cove (Manteo), 1993-2014; 4905; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Pirates Cove (Manteo))
      - Real Escapes (Duck), 1978-1995; 4906; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Real Escapes (Duck))
      - Resort Central (Kitty Hawk), 1994-1995; 4907; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Resort Central (Kitty Hawk))
      - Resort Realty (Kitty Hawk), 1994-1996; 4908; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Resort Realty (Kitty Hawk))
      - Resort Realtys Homes and Homesites, 1994-1995; 4909; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Resort Realtys Homes and Homesites)
      - Resort Rental Properties (Duck), 1994-1995; 4910; Outer Banks History Center (Folder Resort Rental Properties (Duck))